<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[MyFitness Suites]]></title><description><![CDATA[The future of fitness looks different.  Mix and match all your favorite fitness classes in one state of the art location.  Seeing is believing:] ]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/blog</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 10:12:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Morning Routine: A New Day Is Dawning Part 4: ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Once you have your plan, it’s time to start. As with most new adventures, you don’t want to set yourself up for failure, so ease into...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/morning-routine-a-new-day-is-dawning-part-4</link><guid isPermaLink="false">635c7d89fb28db0f75630121</guid><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 02:31:03 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_eb10ee3b92b248a29143addd70270961~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>marybethellis</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Once you have your plan, <strong>it’s time to start</strong>. As with most new adventures, you don’t want to set yourself up for failure, so ease into your new morning routine. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_eb10ee3b92b248a29143addd70270961~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Here are three tips that helped me get started: </p>

<p><strong>1. Set your alarm out of arm’s reach</strong> so you physically have to get up to turn it off. Then immediately go and wash your face with ice-cold water. Not only will the cold water wake you up, but it helps reduce the puffiness around your eyes and has been shown to have <strong>great health benefits for your skin</strong>. </p>

<p><strong>2. Get rehydrated.</strong> Our bodies are comprised of 50-70% water and we lose a good deal of hydration while we sleep. <strong>Water is the fuel of our existence</strong>, so replenishment is essential upon waking. Studies show that adding some sea salt with lemon to a large cup of water will actually help kick start the rehydration of your cells. </p>

<p><strong>3. Do 30 jumping jacks followed by 10 minutes of stretching</strong> while focusing on your breath. The jumping jacks will break you out of your circadian rhythm and the breathwork will aid in re-oxygenation, stimulate your lymphatic system, and increase endorphins. Simply put, if you take deep focused breaths from your diaphragm and extend your exhale you will i<strong>mprove health, immunity, and stress.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Getting IT- Tweaking</strong></p>
<p>After a few weeks of waking up early, <strong>your internal clock will start to align with the alarm</strong>. You’ll start to find that you wake up with more ease and often without needing the alarm at all. </p>

<p>This is also the time to start evaluating what is working and what isn’t. As a general rule, <strong>we don’t see the immediate benefits of most things right away</strong>. Avoid writing off something as a failure until you’ve given it some time to evolve. </p>

<p>After 30 days you can start tweaking your morning routine based on results and interest. <strong>The whole point of this exercise was to find enjoyment and growth</strong>. Make a list of your current morning habits and a second list of new adjustments you’d like to try. Remove the ones that aren’t working for you and replace them with something else from each of the SAVER buckets. </p>

<p>Whatever you do, just make sure you keep it <strong>fun and interesting</strong>. </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Morning Routine: A New Day is Dawning Part 3: The How--Breaking Down the Habit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Part 3 of our Morning Routine series discusses how to apply a new habit. Start with the H – Health – The Anchor that Holds Us Back or...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/morning-routine-a-new-day-is-dawning-part-3-the-how-breaking-down-the-habit</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63573f0aca808b60d76fa2bf</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 16:00:54 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_2ac31047989a4b3aae094051c5c75b67~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Part 3 of our Morning Routine series discusses <strong>how</strong> to apply a new habit. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_2ac31047989a4b3aae094051c5c75b67~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Start with the H – Health – The Anchor that Holds Us Back or Sets us Free</strong></p>
<p>Our<strong> health</strong> is <strong>the most important thing</strong> to get right in our life. Sure, we need many other things like family, love, purpose, and shelter, but <strong>we are nothing without our health</strong>. </p>

<p>Don’t believe me? </p>

<p>Then why did the world come to a complete halt in 2020 to keep us all healthy? Or why do our elders tell us to “<strong>value our health while we have it</strong>”? </p>

<p>While I’ve come to believe it’s <strong>our purpose that drives us</strong>, it’s <strong>not until our health is in order that the clarity of this purpose comes into view</strong>. </p>

<p>Over a period of several years, I lost sight of my health through overindulgence of alcohol, poor eating, and a lack of exercise.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Once I <strong>quit the booze, started eating right, and exercised regularly</strong>, everything seemed to become <strong>clearer</strong>. </p>

<p>If you aim to get nothing else from a morning routine, <strong>start by waking up just a few minutes earlier to do some physical exercise</strong>. </p>

<p><strong>A BIT of Planning – Plan a List </strong></p>
<p>The best place to start is <a href="https://halelrod.com/ep-25-life-savers-for-a-miracle-morning/" target="_blank" >Hal Elrod’s SAVERS</a> when researching what might make for a truly miraculous morning experience. </p>

<p>Hal is the Steve Jobs of the morning routine and has sold over a million copies of his book <em>The Miracle Morning</em>. He lays out a <strong>systematic and practical approach to starting the day</strong> through an acronym and system he calls the SAVERS. </p>

<p><strong>S- Silence </strong></p>
<p><strong>“We can learn more from an hour of silence than we can in a year from books.” – Matthew Kelly</strong></p>
<p>Three Ideas:</p>
<p>· Meditation – Try apps like <em>Headspace, Calm, </em>and<em> Insight Timer</em></p>
<p>· Wim Hof Breathing – Check out the free app and his YouTube videos</p>
<p>· Mindfulness – Check out <em>Aura </em>and <em>Breethe</em> apps</p>

<p><strong>A-Affirmations </strong></p>
<p><strong>“An affirmation opens the door.</strong> <strong>It’s a beginning point on the path to change.” – Louise L. Hay</strong></p>
<p>Three Ideas:</p>
<p>· YouTube has lots of videos with guided affirmations. Pick one that speaks to you. </p>
<p>· Write out a list of 5 or so affirmations each morning. </p>
<p>· Incorporate your list in your meditation. Say the affirmations over and over and block out the rest. </p>

<p><strong>V- Visualization </strong></p>
<p><strong><em>“Visualization is daydreaming with a purpose.” – Bo Bennett</em></strong></p>
<p>Three Ideas:</p>
<p>· Imagine yourself completing each task you have on your to-do list.</p>
<p>· Imagine yourself succeeding with the <strong>one thing </strong>that is <strong>most important</strong> that day.</p>
<p>· Imagine yourself being exactly where you want to be a year from now.</p>

<p><strong>E – Exercise </strong></p>
<p><strong>“Exercise is the key, not only to physical health, but to peace of mind.” – Nelson Mandela</strong></p>
<p>Three Ideas:</p>
<p>· 20 minutes of strength and weight training</p>
<p>· 20 minutes of cardio or functional fitness</p>
<p>· 20 minutes of yoga or stretching. YouTube has great free yoga lessons! </p>

<p><strong>R – Reading </strong></p>
<p><strong>“Reading is a way for me to expand my mind, open my eyes, and fill up my heart” – Oprah Winfrey</strong></p>
<p>Three Ideas:</p>
<p>· Something for spiritual growth. One of my favorites is <em>The Gifts of Imperfection</em> by Rene Brown </p>
<p>· Something for personal growth. One of my favorites is <em>12 Rules for Life</em>  by Jordon Peterson</p>
<p>· Something mindless that spurs creativity. One of my favorites is <em>Unlimited Memory </em>by <em> </em>Kevin Horsley </p>

<p><strong>S- Scribing </strong></p>
<p><strong>“The written word is the strongest source of power in the entire universe.” – Gary Halbert</strong></p>
<p>Three Ideas:</p>
<p>· Journaling: Write out your thoughts, fears, and ideas. (Tons of secure apps for this as well)</p>
<p>· Drawing or Sketching: Don’t worry if you're no Monet. No matter your skill level, this simple practice will spur creativity and ideas through the activation of left and right brain neurons. </p>
<p>· Articles, blog, or a book- Just as is the case with sketching, it's the practice, not the purpose. </p>

<p>Want some time to focus on your breath and dedicate your mind to movement?<strong> Yoga is a great way to increase mindfulness and invite creativity. </strong>We have <a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/classes?category=d25617b5-34ca-4637-a16e-a1e096f27783" target="_blank" ><u>all kinds of classes on offer</u></a>.  </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Morning Routine: A New Day is Dawning Part 2: 5 Reasons Why It's Worth Quitting the Snooze]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Why – 5 Reasons Why it’s Worth Quitting the Snooze Every successful change starts with a compelling "why." How about five of them?...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/morning-routine-a-new-day-is-dawning-part-2-5-reasons-why-it-s-worth-quitting-the-snooze</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63536226bb76eb484f037546</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 03:50:14 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_43d259bb56cd4f3ca313e9bc96240c66~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The Why – 5 Reasons Why it’s Worth Quitting the Snooze </strong></p>
<p>Every successful change starts with a compelling "why." How about five of them?</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_43d259bb56cd4f3ca313e9bc96240c66~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Reason #1: It’s All About You </strong></p>
<p>It’s never good to be entirely selfish, unless of course it’s <strong>good for you and doesn’t disrupt the lives of those you love</strong>. </p>

<p>Imagine having 2 or 3 hours every single day <strong>entirely to yourself</strong> without the disruption of work, the kids, or life in general. What have you always wanted to do but haven’t had the time for? What skills, hobbies, or self-indulgences can you not justify during “normal” hours of operation? <strong>What if you could squeeze 14-21 more hours out of the week</strong> all for your own enjoyment? </p>

<p><strong>It can be done</strong> if you learn good sleep habits and wake up quietly without disrupting your live-in companions. </p>

<p><strong>Reason #2: You Require Time Solely For Your Own Benefit</strong></p>
<p>“Self-care is giving the world the best of you, instead of what’s left of you.” – Katie Reed</p>

<p>The better you feel, the more you can give back to those around you. We live in a culture that seemingly juxtaposes this reality by asking more from us while independently shaming those that benefit for self-purpose.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>But why must everything be so narrowly sighted? Can’t we <strong>balance a self-benefit while still giving to others</strong>? </p>

<p>The answer is<strong> yes</strong>, we can, and <strong>we need a balance of both</strong>. As our families and careers grow, we lose some of the independence that once shaped us. <strong>The morning hours allow you to take your early independence back</strong> and focus on a happy, healthy you. </p>

<p><strong>Reason #3: Early Risers Achieve More Success </strong></p>
<p>We hear stories all the time of successful people waking up early and sticking to a strict morning routine. The late Kobe Bryant was famous for 4:30 AM wake-ups. Every now and then we will see publications touting the contrary, but the lion's share of <strong>publicity remains in favor of the early risers</strong>. </p>

<p>But is there any truth to all this? </p>

<p>Research would suggest a resounding “<strong>yes</strong>."</p>

<p>A recent publication on <a href="https://www.inc.com/laura-garnett/the-scientific-reason-why-being-a-morning-person-will-make-you-more-successful.html" target="_blank" >Inc.com</a> looked at two studies from the scientific community. According to Harvard Biologist Christoph Randler, “<strong>there is a strong correlation between morning people and proactivity</strong>.” His research showed markedly more proactivity amongst the early rising crew in comparison to those that slept in later, longer, or used weekends to “catch up." </p>

<p><strong>Reason #4 for an early rise: early risers are happier</strong></p>
<p>Another study by the <a href="https://www.today.com/health/morning-people-are-happier-night-owls-study-suggests-1C9381787" target="_blank" >University of Toronto</a> reported that morning people were happier. </p>

<p>Researchers Renee Bliss and Lynn Hasher studied sleep patterns and conducted surveys of 700 adults of various ages.<strong> Participants that got up early and had morning routines reported being happier</strong> than those that didn’t. </p>

<p>Those with strict morning routines tend to feel more prepared for the day, thus setting themselves up for better outcomes. </p>

<p><strong>Reason #5 for an early rise: early risers stay out of trouble</strong></p>
<p>Are you prone to making bad decisions? </p>

<p>Your sleep may have something to do with that.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Studies show that <strong>poor sleep dramatically reduces cognitive ability</strong>. In addition, those of you that have ever indulged in the late-night bar scene can attest, to some degree, that the adage <strong>“nothing good happens after midnight” is, in part, true</strong>. </p>

<p>While most don’t fall victim to staying out at all hours of the night, some of us, myself included, seem more prone to its allure. With repetition, this so-called "routine" wreaks havoc on your productivity. </p>

<p>However, <strong>once you fall in love with a morning routine this becomes almost a non-issue</strong>. What I have found is that over time <strong>your mornings become so special that you don’t want to risk messing with your routine</strong>. </p>

<p>I went from never wanting to miss a party to never wanting to miss my 5 AM alarm. Talk about a 180-degree shift.</p>

<p>I'll see you in a couple days with Part 3. In the meantime, give yourself a great reason to avoid hitting the snooze--<a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/classes" target="_blank" ><u>join us for one of our early classes</u></a>!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Morning Routine: A New Day is Dawning Part 1: Welcome to the Rest of Your Life!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today we're launching a series called "A New Day is Dawning." It focuses on routine and habit- building, particularly in the morning. For...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/a-new-day-is-dawning-part-1-welcome-to-the-rest-of-your-life</link><guid isPermaLink="false">634e0bfbc93f05fca47ef46c</guid><category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 16:00:19 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_694f945630a04c4a8ad8c78bf191c3cf~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today we're launching a series called "A New Day is Dawning." It focuses on <strong>routine and habit- building</strong>, particularly in the morning. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_694f945630a04c4a8ad8c78bf191c3cf~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>For a couple of years now I’ve been on a search to hack life in such a way that I get more juice for the squeeze. </p>

<p>It all started with my “Miracle Morning Routine,” then accelerated after the passing of my dad at the young age of 60. </p>

<p>After reading Hal Elrod’s famous book <em>The Miracle Morning</em>, I committed myself to try to quit the snooze button for good. As a father of three, I saw it as a way to selfishly indulge in any and all of my favorite pastimes without hurting anyone. I also had planned to use my morning as a way to get healthy and start each day optimally. </p>

<p>As it turns out, this simple habit did everything I had hoped for, and more.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>My morning routine has changed my life in such a way that I feel obligated to divulge the learnings and failures of this journey. </p>

<p>I’ll share that with you for the next few days by laying out the <strong>why, how, </strong>and <strong>what</strong> behind the years of research and trial I’ve done with this. </p>

<p>Here's what we'll explore: </p><ul>
  <li>The 5 Reasons Why It's Worth Quitting the Snooze</li>
  <li>How to Put the Habit Into Action</li>
  <li>Staying On Target</li>
  <li>Focus on Purpose</li>
  <li>Considering Your Routine</li>
</ul><p>The bedrock of building lasting habits is to make a plan, meet with others, and switch up the content! We have an easy, built-in, and fun way to do that: Join us for our classes. Check out our many offerings <a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/classes" target="_blank" ><u>here</u></a>. You can go several days in a row without repeating even the type of class you're taking! </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Stop Making Excuses! Avoid The Exits]]></title><description><![CDATA[We all have a friend, family member, or loved one who seems to weasel their way out of every personal responsibility via the “excuse...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/avoid-the-exits</link><guid isPermaLink="false">634a1db45386cc8de6cd5f26</guid><category><![CDATA[health and wellness]]></category><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 03:27:14 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_b88ab92730ed431584ad4a6e1b245cf7~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_895,h_666,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We all have a friend, family member, or loved one who seems to weasel their way out of every personal responsibility via the “<strong>excuse exit</strong>”.  </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_b88ab92730ed431584ad4a6e1b245cf7~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_895,h_666,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>The excuse exit opens the door for a person to <strong>escape quickly with little or no accountability</strong><strong>.</strong> </p>

<p>We all have this tendency at times-- to look for easy outs. So, before any of you have a chance to make an excuse to stop reading this, let’s dive in…</p>

<p>Rich was an awkward kid. He worked hard to fit in with his classmates, but a lack of athletic ability and an eye patch to go along with it made for a tough childhood.  When Rich was in 5th grade, he stumbled upon swimming.</p>

<p>It was at this time that he realized that through swimming, he could close the gap between himself and others by <strong>outworking</strong> them.  For the next 10 years of his life, this "secret" served him well.  Rich graduated at the top of his class and received a full ride to swim and study at Stanford University. </p>

<p>The next 10 years of his life however would not be so pleasant. In college, Rich found his way into alcohol and drugs.  Like many, this wasn’t a free fall, but a slow and painful stumble downhill. It was a slide that left him alone, broke, and 50 pounds overweight. </p>
<p>It was at this time that Rich, much like David Goggins and others before them, made a decision. </p>

<p>That decision was to <strong>stop making excuses</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>How?</strong></p>

<p>The best-selling author, speaker, and ex-Navy Seal Jocko Willink explains excuses in a simple but profound way when he says, “They are all lies. <strong>Every single excuse is a lie.</strong>”</p>
<p> </p>
<p>He’s not wrong.  </p>

<p>When we say we don’t have time it is a lie. When we say we are too old, too busy, too scared, too embarrassed, it is all a lie. Instead, what is really going on is that we don’t want to go through the pain of facing the truth. </p>

<p>Excuses give us exits or, at the very least, help us bypass the truth. It is only when we are honest with ourselves that we realize this. Therefore, the key to stopping excuses is to <strong>seek and pursue the truth</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>Rich Roll Today</strong></p>

<p>Today, Rich Roll is one of the world’s most famous ultra-endurance athletes and, at the age of 55, is 20 years sober. He’s also a father to four, husband, and a bestselling author. He has one of the most downloaded podcasts in the world. </p>

<p>In one of those podcasts, Rich was asked how he did it. His answer was that he <strong>stopped listening to the lies and misguided beliefs</strong> that he now calls excuses.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>What to do instead? </p>

<p>Seek the truth from within<strong> and avoid all exits.</strong></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Carb UN-Loading]]></title><description><![CDATA[Could too many carbohydrates, or carbohydrate consumption at the wrong time be cannonballing your fat loss? Discover the dirty little...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/carb-un-loading</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6344e77ef3d5ca6cfea1b2cf</guid><category><![CDATA[health and wellness]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 17:00:21 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_f0771dfe9603478f843467f3df465352~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Could too many carbohydrates, or <strong>carbohydrate consumption at the wrong time</strong> be <strong>cannonballing your fat loss</strong>? Discover the dirty little secrets of these fast fat producing macronutrients.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_f0771dfe9603478f843467f3df465352~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Understanding what to eat and when is complicated. <strong>Carbohydrates by themselves aren’t bad. </strong>The issue is in the <strong>type of carbs</strong> we eat, <strong>when </strong>we eat them, and, of course, <strong>the amount</strong>. If you are trying to lose weight, these little devils could be hurting your progress if you aren’t approaching these three factors correctly.  </p>

<p>Let’s break down what carbs to target, when to avoid them, and how much to eat so you don’t waste your workout. </p>

<p><strong>What Carbs to Eat</strong></p>
<p>This one is easy. Just eat <strong>real, whole foods</strong>, and you will be eating the right carbs. That means <strong>cutting the packaged goods</strong>! Cereal, pretzels, bread, chips, and added sugar may taste good, but they are doing more harm than good for our health. Get your carbs from <strong>fiber-rich veggies, fruits, and real food</strong>!   </p>

<p><strong>When to Eat Them  </strong></p>
<p>Timing might be the most important aspect of carb knowledge to put into play. Many of us <strong>burn stored carbs in the blood and barely tap into burning stored fat</strong>.  If a hard workout is worth 500 calories (don’t trust your watches here-- they are just an algorithm), then how often might you eat 500 calories worth of carbs after your workout and only burn off what you just consumed?  </p>

<p>Try to eat<strong> fiber-rich fruits and vegetables early in the day for energy</strong> but <strong>avoid eating carbohydrates right before or for 2 hours after completing your workout</strong>. If one must eat post-workout to assure you burn stored fat and not just carbs in the bloodstream, then <strong>nuts, lean meats,</strong> and even a good number of <strong>vegetables</strong> are a good choice.  </p>

<p><strong>How Much to Eat</strong></p>
<p>Portion control, particularly with carbs, is a nightmare. Let’s use a couple examples to drive this point home. It’s normal to eat a whole bag of microwave popcorn for most, right?  </p>

<p>Did you know <strong>that little bag has 6 servings</strong> in it? </p>

<p>When it comes to refined carbs and processed foods, we can plow through a day’s worth of calories without even satisfying our hunger. We love to “guesstimate” serving size. </p>

<p>The American Academy of Nutrition recommends we get 45% of our diet from carbohydrates. I call bullshit. It never was this way prior to 1982 and the introduction of the nutritional pyramid. It’s only been in the last 100 years since the Industrial Revolution and the growth of the “big four” food industry that carbs have been pushed on us at such a high level.  </p>

<p>The macros here aren’t important but understand<strong> if you eat 45% carbs, it will be hard to stay under your calorie limit</strong> because they simply aren’t filling. </p>

<p>If you're struggling to lose weight, start cutting back on carbs and trying to <strong>eliminate all refined and processed ones that provide empty calories to your diet</strong>. Furthermore, play around with <strong>limiting your eating post-workout for 2 hours</strong> or at least only targeting <strong>protein and or healthy fats</strong>.  </p>

<p>Looking for a great workout that's totally different from the one you did yesterday? We are waiting here on the West Side for you! <a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/classes" target="_blank" ><u>Check out the wild variety of classes we offer every single day</u></a>!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cutting Ties With Food is Like Dumping Your Ex]]></title><description><![CDATA[Our relationship with food draws similarity to dating an ex-girlfriend or boyfriend. We know it didn’t work the first time, that it’s not...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/cutting-ties-with-food-is-like-dumping-your-ex</link><guid isPermaLink="false">633fc486b88f7a51afa6070b</guid><category><![CDATA[diet]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 16:00:29 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_4ba14ebf2d3f4c659b97234e5b6cb9eb~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our relationship with food draws similarity to dating an ex-girlfriend or boyfriend. We know it didn’t work the first time, that it’s not good for us, and yet the comfort ropes us back in until we find a better alternative. <strong>How can we apply this analogy to our diet? </strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_4ba14ebf2d3f4c659b97234e5b6cb9eb~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Understanding this analogy is helpful when we go to look at changes to our diet.  </p>
<p>We can’t, and truly aren’t making a change unless we experience a bit of discomfort. <strong> Until we break ties completely for a while, we are blind to the issues.</strong> Too often we convince ourselves it’s getting better and put up with bad habits until they present another glaring defect. </p>

<p>It is usually at this time that we <strong>rediscover our internal motivations</strong> and make a swift and aggressive change.  </p>

<p>Eventually, though, trial and error (and even self-punishment), we say “enough is enough” and<strong> break free</strong> from the ball and chain holding us back from being a better version of ourselves. </p>

<p>With any relationship, even with food, we have to realize it’s not easy to break ties. </p>
<p>More importantly, we must believe there is something better and refuse to settle.  </p>

<p><strong>It’s only when we experience what good feels like that we truly get motivated.  </strong></p>

<p>Might it then be helpful then for us to practice playing the field with our food selections?  </p>
<p>We simply <strong>can’t outwork our diets no matter what we do</strong>.  It’s not going to work out unless we break ties completely with something once loved but is <strong>no longer good for us</strong>.  </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Play the field like this and you will likely see there are better fish in the pond.  Yes, you might get drunk one night and pick up the phone (I mean bag of chips.)</p>
<p>  </p>
<p>However, if we experience something <strong>better</strong>, even if just for a short time, we learn something new about ourselves.  We get better over time with breaking off toxic relationships.</p>

<p>In much the same way we improve changing our diet through the routine practice of uncomfortable change. It’s a messy process, and one full of emotional rollercoasters, but it’s always worth it in the end.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Cut Fat Quick Formula ]]></title><description><![CDATA[In the MyFitness Suites fitness community, we advocate for healthy, sustainable transformation. It’s a culture of consistency,...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/the-cut-fat-quick-formula</link><guid isPermaLink="false">633a357e8d28418cb516833a</guid><category><![CDATA[healthy dine in options]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 16:03:44 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_a7d8cec9be1c48c2bbd201fbe8634353~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the MyFitness Suites fitness community, we advocate for<strong> healthy, sustainable transformation</strong>. It’s a culture of <strong>consistency, repetition, practice, and transparency</strong>.  </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_a7d8cec9be1c48c2bbd201fbe8634353~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Rarely, if ever, do we offer people the quick fix or talk dramatic short-term results. <strong>Real weight loss</strong>, the kind that comes off and stays off, typically happens by<strong> increasing your metabolic rate</strong> through improved <strong>muscle mass percentage</strong>, <strong>increased water</strong>, and <strong>decreased body fat</strong>.  </p>

<p>For the average person, losing fat at a rate of roughly <strong>1-2 pounds a week</strong> while <strong>increasing muscle and strength</strong> is a good goal. </p>

<p>Occasionally, we meet people who want quick short-term results for an upcoming wedding, or vacation-- or they want a “summer cut” fast.  Is there a <strong>healthy</strong> way to do this <strong>without disrupting your metabolism</strong> and creating the dreaded <strong>rebound effect</strong>? </p>

<p>The answer is <strong>yes</strong>.</p>

<p>We will lay out the formula here, but know <strong>it’s not easy</strong>.  This technique is meant for the <strong>short term</strong>. Often those who cycle their workouts and diet will use this for a summer cut, then spend the fall and winter building strength and habit. This is done <strong>without hyper-focus on counting</strong>. </p>

<p>Here's the formula:</p>

<p><strong>Low Carb Whole Food Diet + Increased Water + Increased Activity = Accelerated Fat Loss</strong></p>
<p><strong>Low Carb Whole Food Diet</strong></p>

<p><strong>Keto works</strong> because it <strong>restricts carbohydrates</strong>, which are the bodies main source of energy.  By doing so, the body starts to <strong>break down stored fats</strong> and <strong>creates ketones</strong> to be used for energy production.  In a sense, you are <strong>restricting fat producing fuel</strong> and using your body's own fat reserves for <strong>energy</strong> instead.  </p>

<p><strong>Whole foods</strong> are fruits, veggies, nuts, seeds, fish, lean meats, and oils found naturally in our environment. <strong>Restrict your carb intake to under 20%</strong> of your total diet (less than 10% for most keto followers) and <strong>eat only whole foods</strong>. Do this and you will find the body in a <strong>fat-burning state</strong>. </p>

<p><strong>Added Tip:</strong> Sometimes, headaches and dizziness can result without eating a cup of berries or an apple first thing in the morning.  While Keto restricts  sugars and carbs, the sugar packaged with the<strong> fiber in fruit</strong> doesn’t seem to break the cycle for most.  </p>

<p><strong>Increased Water</strong></p>
<p>The studies are all over the place concerning the relationshipe between water intake and fat loss. Results are dependent on the individual, but for most, <strong>3 liters of spring water a day</strong> will assist dramatically in weight loss by <strong>curbing your appetite, improving your metabolic rate</strong>, and helping <strong>speed up the rate with which fat leaves the body</strong>.  </p>

<p><strong>Added Tip:</strong> Add <strong>six to eight twists of pink Himalayan sea salt</strong> to your first H20 of the day to help <strong>increase your water storage</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>Increased Activity</strong></p>
<p>The summer months lend themselves to increased activity, but for a quick cut, focus on <strong>short burst of high intensity</strong>.  Anything that is steady (walking, jogging, etc) will pale in comparison to <strong>intense weight training, sprints, or any level of high-intensity training</strong> in intervals.  </p>

<p>Sometimes, making any change, no matter how small, seems like an Everest-like endeavor.  Buth when it comes to our health, we have to <strong>make time</strong> and <strong>have some foresight</strong> on the future benefits. It’s at the times we feel <strong>overwhelmed</strong> that a<strong> renewed focus on health</strong> is needed <strong>most</strong>. </p>

<p>But <strong>where do we start and what do we do</strong>?  </p>

<p>We can develop <strong>good habits</strong>. It’s often at the times we make healthy additions to our lives that <strong>every aspect of it gets easier</strong>. <strong>Energy, money</strong>, and <strong>time</strong> become <strong>more available</strong> when we avoid thinking and just <strong>do</strong>.  </p>

<p>If you'd like to achieve your fitness goals in the fastest, most efficient way, check out <a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/instructors" target="_blank" ><u>personal training</u></a> and our wide variety of <a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/classes" target="_blank" ><u>group courses</u></a><u>,</u> including <a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/classes?category=b378f103-cfb8-4895-8984-95cfb49724a7" target="_blank" ><u>HIIT</u></a>! </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Try Testosterone (Yes, Women Too)]]></title><description><![CDATA[Want to increase your strength, promote muscle growth, boost your energy, and increase your libido?  Try testosterone-- yes, women too!...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/try-testosterone-yes-women-too-natural-cincinnati</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63363a8e473040a5f893819e</guid><category><![CDATA[health and wellness]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 02:05:23 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_a280d01ab01845839c7f505ee6c0646e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Want to increase your <strong>strength</strong>, promote <strong>muscle growth</strong>, boost your <strong>energy</strong>, and increase your <strong>libido?</strong>  Try <strong>testosterone</strong>-- yes, <strong>women too</strong>! </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_a280d01ab01845839c7f505ee6c0646e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Testosterone is an important hormone for b<strong>oth men and women,</strong> and it often decreases as we age.  The good news is most can boost this number significantly in an <strong>all-natural way</strong>.  </p>

<p>As many of you know, we aren’t big proponents of medications, supplements, or the overuse of vitamins. The reason is for this is twofold. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>First, often, <strong>this stuff doesn’t even work</strong>. Many of the vitamins and minerals we consume in supplements <strong>don’t properly absorb when they aren’t packed in the food</strong>. In many cases, we just consume them and pee them back out. </p>

<p>The second reason we rarely encourage</p>

<p> “quick fixes” has to do with the laws of nature. When we disrupt the homeostasis and finely tuned balance within the body in a quick and orderly fashion, <strong>we often get a rebound</strong> now or later of unintended consequences.  </p>

<p>There are, however, some exceptions to this rule. Certain supplements, vitamins, and even occasionally medications can be beneficial<strong> if used correctly</strong>.  </p>

<p>One of these exceptions is <strong>testosterone regulation</strong>.  </p>


<p>Here are 4 ways to <strong>naturally boost your testosterone </strong>by up to 25 percent. </p>

<p>1. <strong>Strength train:</strong> Lifting weights is a <strong>proven</strong> method of increasing testosterone.  Many of our members already do this. If you want to further increase testosterone from strength training, then make sure you do <strong>compound exercises</strong> that work the biggest muscles in the body.  Maybe you don’t like doing chest work or legs? Encourage yourself to <strong>work muscles in your body you often neglect</strong> for simple testosterone-building effects. </p>

<p>2. <strong>Eat more whole foods</strong>: Whole foods break down more slowly and are more nutrient dense. <strong>Chew your food thoroughly</strong> and increase the <strong>consumption of non-packaged goods. </strong>Your body will reward you with <strong>more te</strong></p>

<p><strong>stosterone</strong>.  </p>

<p>3. <strong>Vitamin D and Vitamin K</strong>: Did you know <strong>Vitamin D and Vitamin K, when used together,</strong> can <strong>increase your testosterone</strong>?  In fact, if we take too much Vitamin D without Vitamin K, it can lead to kidney stones and often doesn’t absorb as well.  The good news is you can find these quality vitamins packaged together when you search online!  </p>

<p>4. <strong>DHEA</strong>: Dehydroepiandrosterone is a hormone produced by the adrenal glands that <strong>,naturally decreases after the age of 30</strong>. It’s an important building block to promoting hormone production and regulation. When we<strong>, supplement DHEA</strong> in conjunction with vitamin D and K, studies have shown we can <strong>,increase our testosterone by as much as 25%</strong>!</p>


<p>As is always, <strong>do your own research and talk to your doctor. </strong>If you’d like to <strong>boost your testosterone naturally</strong>, consider adding in the strength training of often-neglected muscles, which is <strong>more effective</strong> when you <a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/instructors" target="_blank" ><u>work with one of our fantastic personal trainers</u></a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Muscle Myths]]></title><description><![CDATA[Are any of these three Muscle Myths leaving you stagnant? Go heavy! Always eat plenty of protein Track, count, rest, repeat. Repeat......]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/muscle-myths</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63327cd1044ce21e068dccfe</guid><category><![CDATA[health and wellness]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 16:01:07 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_881a77f196f440118626facfa4050cac~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_788,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are any of these three Muscle Myths leaving you stagnant?  </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_881a77f196f440118626facfa4050cac~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_788,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><ul>
  <li>Go heavy!</li>
  <li>Always eat plenty of protein</li>
  <li>Track, count, rest, repeat. Repeat... repeat... repeat... </li>
</ul><p>We've seen <strong>every single one</strong> of these myths refuted. </p>

<p>Read on to see if any of these are curbing your growth by following antiquated or oversimplified advice. </p>
<h6><strong>Myth #1: You have to go heavy.</strong></h6>
<p>Not always! Building muscle is founded on two main principles: <strong>Progressive overload</strong> and <strong>time under tension</strong>.  </p>

<p>Going heavy is just <strong>one</strong> way to add more load to your muscles.  Don’t believe us?  </p>

<p>Which athletes have the <strong>most impressive quads and glutes</strong>?  </p>

<p>Which athletes have the <strong>biggest shoulders</strong>?  </p>

<p>Which athletes have <strong>tremendous calves</strong>?  </p>

<p>Soccer players and catchers own the right to the best legs and glutes because they are <strong>constantly pushing their leg muscles</strong> for more and more performance and power.  The body responds by giving them more.  </p>

<p>The same can be said for swimmers and their shoulders or gymnasts and their calves. <strong>What the body trains for, the body gets.</strong> </p>

<p>Learn to use explosive and athletic force in <strong>short, repetitive lifts</strong> and your muscles will respond with <strong>growth</strong>. </p>
<h6><strong>Myth #2: You can't get muscles without tons of protein.</strong></h6>
<p>If this were the case, then how did the World's Strongest Man and <a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/service-page/personal-training-w-shane?category=5f6581de-0d80-47c6-a582-b956e2e36782&#38;referral=service_list_widget" target="_blank" ><u>our own trainer Shane</u></a> get so hulkish via vegan diets? </p>

<p>There are 9 essential amino acids in your body. All are important to muscle growth; however, protein comes in lots of variety and forms.  </p>

<p><strong>Gram for gram, protein is the most filling and low calorie</strong> of <a href="https://www.rxlist.com/main_types_of_macronutrients_what_examples_of_each/article.htm" target="_blank" ><u>the three macronutrients</u></a>. Protein is slow to digest, packed with nutrients, and only 4 calories per gram. That means protein is a better<strong> weight loss tool</strong> than muscle-building aid.</p>

<p>For muscle building, however, most studies have shown that<strong> .7 grams of protein per pound of body weight</strong> is sufficient. Since we are lazy mathematicians, humans have oversimplified this over time to be 1 gram per lb. Realistically, however, a 150lb person has sufficient protein for muscle growth if he or she consumes 105 grams. </p>

<p><strong>Carbs</strong> can be a <strong>friend to the tough muscle gainer</strong> and a <strong>foe</strong> to those on a <strong>weight loss venture</strong>. If you're trying to <strong>lose weight and gain muscle</strong>, go for 1 gram of carbs per pound. If you're struggling to<strong> gain weight</strong>, however, stick with .7 grams and load up on carbs to more easily achieve the needed calorie surplus for gains.  </p>
<h6><strong>Myth #3: You have to track and count your reps and rest between sets.</strong></h6>
<p>Wait, what?. It can be difficult to wrap our minds around the idea that this isn't the best way to weight train, because it directly contradicts how many of us were taught to lift.  </p>

<p>Traditionally, lifters are told to push/pull on the upper body Monday, Wednesday, and Friday with leg days in between.  <strong>But what really happens</strong> is we skip most of the leg days and do 3 lazy sets of 10 on the other 3 days.  <strong>This isn’t going to get you anywhere.</strong>  </p>

<p>While you might<strong> think </strong>you are adding weight or reps week to week, <strong>it’s not driven by the same energy output</strong>, nor is your <strong>brain</strong> in the same place each time. Ask <a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/classes?category=5f6581de-0d80-47c6-a582-b956e2e36782" target="_blank" ><u>any of the trainers </u></a>or MFS members that have been onboard for a year or more--they will tell you they have seen gains<strong> beyond what anyone ever expected</strong>.</p>

<p>Why? Because when <strong>you aren’t counting</strong> all the time, but instead being <strong>pushed</strong> by the trainer and your fellow classmates, you give 100% <strong>every single time</strong>.  </p>

<p>It’s the <strong>100</strong>% <strong>effort</strong> combined with <strong>progressive overload</strong>, <strong>increased time under tension</strong>, and <strong>muscle confusion</strong> that creates <strong>fast gains</strong>. </p>

<p>MyFitness Suites is the perfect place for personalized advice on <strong>muscle training</strong> and <strong>nutrition choices</strong>. Try a <a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/booking-calendar/nutrition-consult-w-claire" target="_blank" ><u>consultation with a registered dietitian nutritionist</u></a>. Good food choices plus a <a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/classes?category=5f6581de-0d80-47c6-a582-b956e2e36782" target="_blank" ><u>personal training program</u></a> will help you dodge more Muscle Myths.</p>
<p>  </p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Avoid Health Food Fraud]]></title><description><![CDATA[Do you think you're avoiding empty calories because your pantry is stocked from the "health food aisle"? Not so fast! Let's start with a...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/avoid-health-food-fraud</link><guid isPermaLink="false">632d2bb873dda6f3cb4bd721</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 16:00:24 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_d95f66acaa7845c9b1cfa39a6bfbf74e~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_650,h_544,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do you think you're avoiding empty calories because your pantry is stocked from the "health food aisle"? Not so fast!</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/59e5d4_d95f66acaa7845c9b1cfa39a6bfbf74e~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_650,h_544,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Let's start with a quiz. </strong></p>

<p>What is the healthier option between a fruit smoothie and a bag of M&Ms?  </p>

<p>How about Veggie Straws vs. Doritos?   </p>

<p>Now a tougher one: Which do you think is healthier between Special K Granola or organic chocolate yogurt?</p>

<p> Find out as we peel back the onion on all the “healthy” food that's mislabeled in our grocery stores. But don't worry-- eating for lifelong health</p><hr><p><strong>The Answers</strong></p>

<p><strong>Ten food companies own and control nearly every item we buy at the grocery store.</strong></p>

<p>This is not a good thing!</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>As we have come to learn, bigger isn't better. The larger the company, the more control they have over policy. The result is food lobbyists, marketing heads, and even politicians that willingly allow for bad behavior in the name of big profit.  </p>
<p> </p>
<p>While this isn’t a new phenomenon, marketing has gotten better at <strong>deceiving</strong> us into thinking we are eating healthy foods. At a time when it may seem there is a healthy food push, more and more of our food options are <strong>mislabeled</strong> as “natural”, “whole-grain”, “low sodium”, “sugar free”, “gluten free,” “low fat”, and a slew of others meritless descriptions.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>According to recently published studies analyzing over 40,000 grocery store items, <strong>between 60-74% of products on the shelf have added sugar</strong>.   </p>
<p> </p>
<p>The unfortunate truth is that <strong>the vast majority of packaged goods are bad for us</strong>!  </p>
<p> </p>
<p>While added sugar is the main culprit thanks to its addicting and profit-boosting properties, hundreds of other <strong>artificial ingredients also wreak havoc</strong>. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>If it’s on a shelf, you can pretty much bet it has ingredients you’ve never heard of that spike our insulin levels, destroy our microbiome, and provide little to no nutritional value. <strong>These empty calories do nothing but leave us craving more!</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Back to the quiz for a moment.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>While sugar is a naturally occurring byproduct of fruit, <strong>when we juice our fruit, we eliminate fiber meant to limit our consumption and slow down absorption</strong>.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>You likely can't eat 5 apples or 4 bananas with ease, right?</p>
<p> </p>
<p>But, when juiced, it's no problem at all. Our smoothie example at the top highlights this. A quick nutritional review of several different brands of medium-sized strawberry banana smoothies labeled as "green" or "healthy" showed <strong>an average of 49 grams of sugar</strong>. Many even have added sugar or juice concentrates.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Given that the rest of the world consumes <strong>less than 30 grams in total sugar a day</strong>, this is a bad snack. While not recommending it, we would be better off snacking on Peanut M&M's; these boast 14 grams per serving.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Okay, so now what about Veggie Straws, granola, and yogurts? Side by side, <strong>Veggie Straws are no healthier than Doritos</strong> and neither provide the body with anything but... you guessed it... more empty calories. <strong>Store-bought granolas and yogurts are notoriously low in nutritional value</strong> and full of added ingredients.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The only real way to lose weight, add muscle, and improve our health is to eat more whole foods and avoid processed packaged goods as much as possible. </strong></p><hr><p> <strong>How to Get Started With Whole Foods</strong></p><ul>
  <li>Try to consume <strong>80 percent or greater of your calories through whole foods</strong>. </li>
  <li>When choosing packaged items look for those that have the<strong> lowest numbers of ingredients</strong>. </li>
  <li><strong>Avoid</strong> anything that has sugar, artificial sugar, vital wheat gluten, hydrogenated oils, sodium nitrates, MSG's, or BHT in the <strong>first 4 ingredients</strong>.</li>
</ul><p>Try to eat 100 percent whole foods for 1 day this week and take note of your body's response and calories consumed. <strong>It's actually fairly difficult to overeat when we cut all the empty calories</strong>. </p>

<p>Over time, if you can make the switch off processed and packaged, you'll notice big changes in energy, fitness, weight, muscle, mental clarity, and overall health.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>So the next time you're tempted to reach for that shiny package on the shelf, ask yourself this: "If we aren't supposed to feed animals our food because it will make them sick, then <strong>why in the hell are we eating it</strong>?"</p>

<p>Don't fight those misleading labels at the grocery store alone! At MyFitness Suites, we offer so much more than group classes and gym sessions. Check out a <a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/booking-calendar/nutrition-consult-w-claire" target="_blank" ><u>consultation with a registered dietitian nutritionist</u></a>. If you'd like to jump-start <strong>your best body</strong> with a <a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/classes?category=5f6581de-0d80-47c6-a582-b956e2e36782" target="_blank" ><u>personal training program</u></a> and nutrition consult, we are here to get you started! </p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Super Foods To Swap Into Your Diet Now!  ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Want one change that will cause you to lose an extra five lbs a month without adding a single workout or requiring you to eat less? Then...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/5-super-foods-to-swap-into-your-diet-now</link><guid isPermaLink="false">62f93405787c28eeaa91918d</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 18:08:17 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_9335536358094151be69d66f5fe4f7a5~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_788,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_9335536358094151be69d66f5fe4f7a5~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_788,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Want one change that will cause you to lose an extra five lbs a month without adding a single workout or requiring you to eat less? </strong></p>

<p><strong>Then read on and commit to the 5 week food swap! </strong></p>

<p><strong>Changing what we eat requires the same motivation, if not more, than increasing our physical exercise.  </strong></p>

<p><strong>For some people, fitness motivation comes from feeling better, more confident, or even more focused.  Others are driven by improved physical strength, endurance, or performance. Whatever the reason, it’s worth noting that swapping just one item from your daily diet and replacing it with a “SUPER FOOD” might double your speed to goal achievement.  </strong></p>

<p><strong>Below we will outline 5 Super Foods to SWAP into your regular diet.  </strong></p>

<p><strong>Try one a week for 5 weeks and the end result will change your energy level, improve your strength, and definitely have you shedding the lbs! In fact</strong>,<strong> this one change should make more difference than adding additional workouts. </strong></p>

<p><strong>Hear me out for a second…</strong></p>

<p><strong>Let’s say you already work out 3-6 hours a week.  You could add one killer 800 calorie workout or you could find 800 less calories by purposefully swapping a routine snack or drink item for something more powerful. </strong></p>

<p><strong>Build up to swapping all five and you’ve decreased your weekly calorie consumption by over 4000 calories!</strong></p>

<p><strong>Given it takes roughly 3500 calories deficit to shed a lb of fat, these swaps equal roughly 5-6lbs extra lbs of fat loss per month! </strong></p>

<p><strong>Let’s look at 5 examples that achieve this!  </strong></p>

<p><strong>1.      Nuts and Seeds For A Snack </strong></p>

<p><strong>These are far higher in calories than almost any other snack. HOWEVER, they are far more filling and loaded with more essential amino acids, omega-3’s, and quality fiber than nearly any singular food item of equal volume.  Nuts, seeds, and their little cousins below sprouts, are all the beginning stages of life.  They are pack with essential nutrients needed to produce far greater outputs of food.  Let’s say you like popcorn.  We rarely eat the 1/3 a microwave bag of popcorn listed as a serving.  We usually eat and possibly even think, a reasonable serving size is a bag.  This is over 450 calories.  Instead</strong>,<strong> eat a serving size of pistachios.  Between slowing the snacking down by opening the damn things and in the amount the nuts fill you up vs popcorn, you will likely be satisfied and more full after the nuts.  1 serving size of pistachios is 170 calories of highly nutrition output. It would only take you 3 days of swapping here to achieve the 800 calories in the example.  </strong></p>

<p><strong>2.      S.M.A.S.H. FISH Instead of Red Meat or Processed Meat</strong></p>

<p><strong>Swap red meat for fish and consider the healthiest of all fish with the S.M.A.S.H. acronym.  Salmon, or the s, is 140 calories per 100g vs that of beef which is 250 for the same weight.  Let’s say you eat 200g as a serving. That’s a difference of 220 calories a day while boosting your nutritional value in amino acids.  After just 4 days of swapping you are down another 880. </strong></p>

<p><strong>3.      Eggs Quiche Instead of Breakfast Carbs</strong></p>

<p><strong>Grab and go breakfast bar?  Maybe a muffin, poptart, or some other packaged and processed refined carb? Swap that poptart for 3 eggs. Highly nutritious and loaded with nutrients, 3 eggs cooked in a breakfast quiche with your favorite leafy greens, peppers, etc will net you less than 110 calories per quiche.  Let’s say you eat 2 quiche instead of the 2 pop tarts that come packaged together( yeah we eat one initially but the other goes down the gullet at some point in small picks and bites).  The two pop tarts in the package yields 420 </strong>calories<strong>. That’s a savings of 310 calories while also cutting a whopping 28 grams of sugar! </strong></p>

<p><strong>4.      Chick Pea Over Pasta</strong></p>

<p><strong>Chick Peas are about as close as you can get to completely fulfilling the nine essential amino acids found in many of our meat proteins.  They are just one essential amino acid short.  Highly nutritious, highly filling, and rich in protein, the </strong>chickpea<strong> pasta swap might be the easiest of all to swallow.  When not overcooked, </strong>chickpea<strong> pasta tastes so similar to regular pasta that I didn’t realize Michelle had made the swap for me one night.  Pasta has 370 calories per 100 grams vs the 170 calories found per 100grams.  4 days of swapping and you are down another 800! </strong></p>

<p><strong>5.      Blend In The Dark Leafy Greens</strong></p>

<p><strong>These aren’t my favorite to eat nor are they my favorite to cook with.  However</strong>,<strong> add them to the grill or blend them with frozen fruits and now they are a little more palpable.  Add your spinach or kale to the egg quiche or blender with some other favorite ingredients and you will fill yourself up with nutrients and fewer calories.  Consider adding dark leafy greens instead of processed meat to your breakfast omelet or blender meal.  </strong></p>

<p><strong>Call to Action:</strong></p>

<p><strong>Pick one swap from the list above.  Grocery shop, plan your replacement and set the stage to start this for 7 days beginning this week.  Rinse and repeat each week until you’ve successfully swapped 5!</strong></p>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hormesis: The What Doesn't Kill Us Tip]]></title><description><![CDATA[There are 1,000,000 types of animals that walk, fly, and roam this earth.  How many of them do you think struggle with obesity, tooth...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/hormesis-the-what-doesn-t-kill-us-tip</link><guid isPermaLink="false">629373252944f6d0db3aba83</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 13:52:11 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_a3454082eb6645e6a46d7b6fa3c116a0~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_788,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_a3454082eb6645e6a46d7b6fa3c116a0~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_788,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>There are 1,000,000 types of animals that walk, fly, and roam this earth.  How many of them do you think struggle with obesity, tooth decay, and diabetes?</p>

<p>The answer, though obvious, may seem shocking.  It’s just us humans and the pets we feed.</p>

<p>What’s with that?  </p>

<p>Despite natural selection making the gene pool stronger, we as humans seem to be getting weaker.    </p>

<p>It is as if we’ve lost touch with the delicate balance within our own bodies. </p>

<p>It hasn't always been this way though.  Chronic diseases have exploded over the last few decades. </p>

<p>Today, it's estimated that 133 million Americans - nearly half of us - have one or more chronic conditions.  What is even more alarming is that this number is nearly 15 million higher than a decade ago. </p>

<p>In fact, <strong>4 in 10 of us now succumb to death or disability</strong> from a combination of two or more chronic conditions.</p>

<p>So what can we learn from our ancestor's diet and behavior that might help us today? </p>

<p>This will be our theme over the next month as we analyze four well-researched and lesser-known tips that will spell out the word <strong>H.O.M.E</strong>. </p>

<p>So without further delay, let’s talk <strong>HORMESIS</strong> in this week’s tip!</p>

<p>Hormesis is defined as a dose-response phenomenon characterized by stress stimulation and high-dose inhibition.  Simply put, there is a benefit to introducing small doses of mild stressors to the body.  Hormesis as a term may be new to you, but it has been studied and validated by its practitioners for years.  </p>

<p>Think of<strong> HORMESIS </strong>as the “what doesn’t kill you makes you stronger” tip.  </p>

<p>Examples would include <strong>ice baths, saunas, exercise, hypoxia, and intermittent fasting</strong>.  </p>

<p>All things we are hearing a lot about these days right? </p>

<p>The reason behind this is that in much the same way some vaccines work, our bodies can become stronger through the introduction of small doses of mild stress.  </p>

<p>To provide an example, scientists have studied the effects of cold exposure on the body.  Thanks to Wim Hof, aka the iceman, millions of people around the world now regularly practice a combination of cold showers, breathwork, and mindfulness exercises.  </p>

<p>Several studies have shown that cold exposure changes the chemical and physical makeup of the body through regulation of the autonomic nervous system and the increase and storage of brown fat(adipose tissue). </p>

<p>Through regular practice, intentional cold exposure helps keep the body’s responses to external stimuli sharp and increases the fuel our bodies need to run a healthy immune response.  </p>

<p>Practitioners of cold showers and ice baths also tout its ability for weight loss, stress reduction, inflammation, and improved mental health. </p>

<p>With regard to this week’s tip, think of hormesis as a helpful tool to hack just about any health goal.  </p>

<p>Trying to lose weight? Then think in terms of boosting your body's response through the introduction of small doses of stressful changes to your diet and exercise routine.  Intermittent fasting, carb restriction, or a month of a whole food-only diet are often very good ways to change your body fast. </p>

<p>Stuck trying to gain muscle? If you’ve been struggling at the same weight and want to add muscle maybe add a pullup, pushup, or squat challenge every day outside of your normal workout for a month.  Start on day one maxing out as many reps as you can in one set and then add small amounts of weight or reps every day for 30 days.  </p>

<p>Think in terms of exercise. In the same way mild doses of stress from your workouts make you stronger, begin to think of other ways to challenge your 5 senses. </p>

<p>Try out hormesis this week and see if you get any immediate results that make health exciting again.  A week of hot classes?  A week of forcing a cold shower every day for 2 mins?  A week of no sugar, or drinking water only, or maybe eating all your meals in a 8-hour window. </p>

<p>Who’s first to join me on the cold showers? Haha( this sounds way worse than the intent behind the question.)  Now get out there and try some hormesis this week and impress your friends with a new word! </p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What Is Wrong With Me?! 4 Major Factors Affecting Health and Homeostasis (We can't ignore these...)]]></title><description><![CDATA[As most of you now know, I’ve been dealing with intermittent “flare-ups” and autoimmune-like symptoms from what all my doctors tell me is...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/what-is-wrong-with-me-4-major-factors-affecting-health-and-homeostasis-we-can-t-ignore-these</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6287d20b414ed27d58776627</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 14:13:37 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_b3cf7ce54b24479cb5bbe506af8b6492~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_788,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_b3cf7ce54b24479cb5bbe506af8b6492~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_788,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>As most of you now know, I’ve been dealing with intermittent “flare-ups” and autoimmune-like symptoms from what all my doctors tell me is PASC, aka. “Long Covid”.  My symptoms include stabbing, sharp, or sometimes “crampy” muscle and joint pain, the sudden onset of crushing fatigue, different kinds of GI distress, numbness/tinkling of my extremities, and occasional bouts of dizziness.  It’s beyond frustrating and at times debilitating.  For days and even weeks, I will feel fine with exception of a couple of nuisance-like symptoms.   Then suddenly, and without much warning, WHAM, it’s back! </p>

<p>As a gym owner and yoga lover, I’ve found this to be particularly challenging because I pride myself on clean eating, healthy living, and being in tune with my body.  Thoughts of doubt go thru my head as to whether I am mentally and physically tough enough. My ego gets in the way and I start to worry about whether family, friends, or beloved gym members can trust my guidance when I can’t seem to fix myself.  </p>

<p>It’s been a long, painful, exhausting, and even insightful battle. </p>

<p>Having said that, I refuse to believe this is happening without purpose or reason.  </p>
<p>Every one of us experiences immense pain, struggle, and hardship in life. While I don’t subscribe to the belief that “everything happens for a reason,” I do believe there is reason to be found in all struggles.  </p>

<p>The difference between these two mantras is simply mindset. While one mantra invites a game of wait and see, the other forces action on our part.  Or to put it another way, it’s much easier to find the bright side while searching for it than it is to wait on the sun to find you.  </p>

<p>To tell someone dealing with a catastrophic event, a life-threatening illness, or an untimely death, that it happened for a “reason,” never seemed to work for me.  But when we seek clarity, seek knowledge, and seek reason, we often do find glimmers of sunshine in the forecast ahead.  </p>

<p>As I continue to work through this, seeking that clarity of “reason” and purpose has now become my focus. </p>

<p>So, since I’ve spent 6 months now researching, learning, and living health experiments, I thought I’d share the four things that clearly stand out in the world of health and wellness.  </p>

<p>Over the next month, in each week’s tip I will roll out one of the four key factors to achieving, optimizing, and even correcting our health. </p>

<p>But before doing so, we need a basic understanding of homeostasis, so let's start there as an introduction to the BIG FOUR health factors. </p>

<p><strong>HOMEOSTASIS</strong></p>
<p>We live in a world today where the pace, diet, and environmental conditioning is disconnected from our natural state of being.  </p>

<p>Homeostasis, as defined by the oxford dictionary, is a tendency toward a relatively stable equilibrium between interdependent elements, especially as maintained by physiological processes.  </p>

<p>When it comes to homeostasis, as humans this balance can be wildly disrupted by too much or not enough of factors that are entirely in our control.  </p>

<p>What in the world does this have to do with sickness and health you might ask? </p>

<p>EVERYTHING!</p>

<p>You see our ancestors and many that walked before us practiced homeostasis with regularity and had a much better understanding of its importance than we do today.  </p>

<p>Homeostasis is why a dog lets its tongue hang out when it is tired, it’s why animals flocked to salt licks, it’s why our bodies are finely regulated at roughly 98.6 degrees and it’s why cold-blooded animals use the environment to regulate their internal temperature.  </p>

<p>But it’s doesn’t just stop there.  It’s not just what’s happening within the part but instead how the part affects the whole.  </p>

<p>Homeostasis explains why when glucose isn’t regulated the body’s feedback loop becomes broken and diabetes forms.  Homeostasis is also at the root cause of MS, Parkinson’s, Crohn’s, IBS, Hashimoto’s, and nearly ever chronic disease of which we are almost 6x more likely to die of today than 100 years ago.</p>

<p>At the forefront of this epidemic is autoimmune disease.  </p>

<p>Today it’s estimated over 50 million or roughly 1 in 6 US adults suffer from autoimmune disease.  </p>

<p>So why are our bodies attacking ourselves at a time when our bodies and gene pool is stronger than ever? </p>

<p>You guessed it.  At the root cause the answer is undoubtedly homeostasis.</p>

<p>Want proof? </p>

<p>There are 1,000,000 types of animals that walk, fly, and roam this earth.  How many of them do you think struggle with obesity, tooth decay, and diabetes, etc?</p>

<p>The answer, though obvious, may seem shocking.  </p>

<p>Yes it’s only humans and the pets we feed that seem to have the problems.   </p>

<p>But it hasn’t always been this way adding more evidence to the fact that we’ve lost touch with the delicate balance within our own bodies. </p>

<p>Anthropologists that study our ancestors note a stark difference in the bones, teeth, gut size, and fats of those that walked before us.  It’s only been in the last 100 years that industrial processes have dramatically changed our diets.  It’s hypothesized that despite our genetic pool getting stronger, the dramatic changes to our diet without evolutionary requirement, have led our health astray. </p>

<p>So what can we learn from our ancestors that might help us find homeostasis today and heal ourselves? </p>

<p>There are <strong>4 factors from all my research that align</strong>: <strong>Healthy Immune Response(Hormesis), Optimized Environment, Mindfulness, and Energy Production. </strong> For memory’s sake these will make up the acronym <strong>HOME</strong>. </p>

<p>Look for Factor ONE, Healthy Immune Response, in Monday’s Tip of the Week! </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 EXPERT MENTAL HEALTH TIPS FOR THE HOLIDAYS]]></title><description><![CDATA[“Have a holly jolly Christmas… it’s the best time of the year...", or is it? Did you know 64 percent of people report a decline in their...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/5-expert-mental-health-tips-for-the-holidays</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61b3a4a7faff920016a6693b</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 19:21:50 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_7b584f4b96764444ae8f8940b9395546~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_534,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_7b584f4b96764444ae8f8940b9395546~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_534,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>“Have a holly jolly Christmas… it’s the best time of the year...", or is it?  </p>

<p>Did you know 64 percent of people report a decline in their mental health during the holidays? </p>

<p>If you find yourself stressed, depressed, or in a funk this December don’t beat yourself up.  There is a good reason for this.  Be it the arrival of the dreary days of winter or the moderately dysfunctional family gatherings, the Holidays are primed for mental health decline.  </p>

<p>Let’s look at some tips from mental health expert (aka Michelle Menke LISW-S) on how to plan and prevail over the holiday blues in this week’s tip! </p>

<p><strong>1. TREAT YOURSELF LIKE SOMEONE ELSE YOU LOVE.  </strong>Why is it that most of us treat other people better than we treat numero uno?  We can’t be our best for others unless we treat ourselves with the same love and attention we might give to a loved one.  The sad truth is, most of us take better care of our beloved pets than we do ourselves.  Think about it, if the dog or cat is suffering from an ear infection, we are quick to get them help.  If we are suffering, we tell ourselves to suck it up and put everyone else first.   The quicker you operate at your best the more helpful you will be to others! </p>

<p><strong>2. GRATITUDE BEFORE ATTITUDE.</strong>  Attitude is a choice.  Gratitude is a state of mind.  The holidays are a great time of year to start a new tradition of writing down all the things you are thankful for. By design, humans are loss-averse, meaning we tend to focus more on things that can harm or disrupt our lives.  A daily gratitude list is an easy way to reverse the narrative towards positivity.  “Change the way you look and things and the things you look at change”- Wayne Dyer </p>

<p><strong>3. PRIORITIZE YOUR TIME.</strong> Manage your time and prioritize to avoid “overbooking.” When we overbook our highly demanded time, it can be extremely stressful.  We end up offering less to more and in return not enjoying the very things we should be grateful for.  Ask yourself if the item on your to-do list fits within your pre-determined guard rails.  If it doesn’t then it is time to practice that “NO.” </p>

<p><strong>4. BE REALISTIC WHEN COMPARING YOURSELF.</strong>  Social media and tv make a hero out of everyone! When we compare our lives to our perception of the lives lead by others, we inevitably feel let down or inferior. Remind yourself that struggle is universal! Instead, make a comparison to yesterday and reward the areas of you have improved. </p>

<p><strong>5. SET BOUNDARIES WITH FAMILY MEMBERS.  </strong>Sometimes when we get together with family members we notice our stress level elevate. This is because unlike social media connections, our families know our weaknesses and how to "push our buttons".  Set boundaries ahead of time with family members about what topics you want to avoid discussing at this year’s holiday party!</p>

<p><strong>TAKE ACTION!</strong></p>

<p>There is something about a good therapist that leaves you saying “duh.”  </p>

<p>Trust me, I’m married to one.  </p>

<p>What I mean by this is that a good therapist makes things so simple and obvious that you leave the discussion thinking, “of course.”  </p>

<p>But, with simplicity comes brilliance!</p>

<p>We aren’t likely to act on the advice we aren’t in agreement with. </p>

<p>While the above tips may seem obvious, if you found yourself relating then chances are you might benefit from putting them into action.  </p>

<p>Quickly scan the list above once more and pick one that you can commit to implementing this Holiday season.  And with that you'll have your tip of the week! </p>

<p><em>If you enjoy our weekly tips, subscribe to our blog.  If you want more content like this follow us on </em>Facebook<em>, </em>Instagram<em>, and our newly released Myfitness Suites Tik Tok page!  Links below.</em></p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/177663297572762" target="_blank" ><u>https://www.facebook.com/groups/177663297572762</u></a> </p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/my_fitness_suites/" target="_blank" ><u>https://www.instagram.com/my_fitness_suites/</u></a> </p>
<p><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@myfitnesssuites?lang=en" target="_blank" ><u>https://www.tiktok.com/@myfitnesssuites?lang=en</u></a> </p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[TIP OF THE WEEK: THE ONE WORD HEALTH HACK]]></title><description><![CDATA[Whether written, spoken, or heard, words are life changing. Think about that for a minute.  How many big events in your life could be...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/tip-of-the-week-the-one-word-health-hack</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61ad55841a309200168289f4</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:23:11 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_337f250fa5aa4006a5297dcb073dcd48~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_534,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_337f250fa5aa4006a5297dcb073dcd48~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_534,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Whether written, spoken, or heard, words are life changing. </p>

<p>Think about that for a minute.  How many big events in your life could be described in a single word?</p>

<p>Words like disappointment, sickness, divorce, fear, and anger might describe times of despair. We hear these words and our past experiences careen into us with a swell of emotion.  </p>

<p>Or, to use a positive example, what might you feel when you hear the good words? Words like promotion, inspiration, love, marriage, joy, and fulfillment.  In just the same way bad words shape our mood, these good words often carry us over, threw, and out of life’s challenges.</p>

<p>However, with over 200,000 words in the English language, only a handful are powerful enough to change one’s mindset.  </p>

<p>So, what if instead of waiting for the words that will change us to arrive, we simply made a list of words we wanted to pursue? </p>

<p>I listened to a Ted Talk recently where a guy did this very thing.  Every day he picked one word to embody.   </p>

<p>On day one he was driving to work when the word <strong>STRONG</strong> just kept popping in his head.  </p>
<p>At the time he’d just lost someone close to him and had been struggling to get out of a deep depression. Not feeling remotely strong in that moment, he decided to fake it for a day to see how his mindset might shift. </p>

<p>The change was so profound it caused him to search for another word the next day.  </p>
<p>He did this every day for a year! Each day picking one word, not always new, sometimes repeated, but just one single word to focus on.</p>

<p>That year changed his life.  </p>

<p>So, I decided to try it myself this week. I did this mainly because it was so simple, but also because later that night a word did in fact randomly keep popping in my head.  </p>

<p>That word was FUN!.  </p>

<p>Maybe needing some fun in my life, I figured “what the hell let’s try.”</p>
<p>Well, to my surprise, it worked!  I found myself beginning to recognize the fun to be had in the little moments.  </p>

<p>It changed my rather ordinary day into one that was truly fun! </p>

<p>As the week wore on and I did this I continued to have a word pop in my head that I wanted to seek the following day.  This worked so well that I wanted to share it with all of you.  </p>

<p>So, with further ado, and after the longest intro of all time, ironically your TIP OF THE WEEK is short. In fact, it’s just one WORD! </p>

<p>Now go find your word for tomorrow and try it!  </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Golden Rule: How One Simple Trick Can Improve Diet, Exercise, Fat Loss, and Muscle Gain]]></title><description><![CDATA[Did you know twenty percent of the food we eat generates eighty percent of our energy? Would you be surprised to learn that eighty...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/the-golden-rule-how-one-simple-trick-can-improve-diet-exercise-fat-loss-and-muscle-gain</link><guid isPermaLink="false">617c39b39457080017f0af4d</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 19:16:17 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_8951d95a2ede405397c71a8386853769~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_534,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_8951d95a2ede405397c71a8386853769~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_534,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Did you know twenty percent of the food we eat generates eighty percent of our energy? Would you be surprised to learn that eighty percent of your grocery bill comes from twenty percent of items purchased?  Have you ever heard that eighty percent of our healthcare resources are gobbled up by twenty percent of patients?  </p>

<p>It’s called Pareto’s Law and it applies to almost every aspect of life. So much so that it is often referred to as the “golden rule” of business because eighty percent of results come from twenty percent of our efforts.  </p>

<p>While believing this may be a tough pill to swallow, it is a tried and true part of life so we might as well aim to choke down the right pills. </p>

<p>So how can we apply Pareto to our fitness plan to maximize our output?   </p>

<p>Let’s brainstorm some practical ways to use the “golden rule” for diet, exercise, fat loss, and muscle growth.  </p>

<p><strong>How to Apply the Golden Rule to Diet?</strong></p>

<p>All good brainstorming exercises start with a question, so let’s start there.  </p>

<p>What twenty percent of food and beverage consumption do you believe to be the biggest hindrance to your energy, fitness goals, and health?  Now make a list.  </p>

<p>Next, analyze the list and ask yourself, “Which of these items do I confidently believe I can cut from my diet first?”  </p>

<p>When doing this use a less is more approach. Focus on items you know are bad, but you believe you can cut. </p>

<p>Now, with these in hand, it's time to implore the “want” power from last week's tip.  Meaning, if you “want” to change or cut these items from your diet then it’s best to understand fully all the motivating reasons you should.  </p>

<p>Start from a standpoint of curiosity instead of a requirement.  Research and learn what sugar, alcohol, unrefined carbs, etc do to your body.  Focus on what you stand to lose by not changing and build a list of possible positive replacements.  Lastly, practice and reward yourself every single time you achieve success in new healthy ways. </p>

<p><strong>How to Apply the Golden Rule to Exercise? </strong></p>

<p>What twenty percent of my exercise routine might produce eighty percent of the result I’m looking for?  Where and when can I add twenty percent more effort, reps, or weight?  </p>

<p>Applying the Pareto principle to exercise is a little tougher because it requires an understanding of the fundamentals of fat loss and muscle gain.  Since not everyone has the same goal, let’s break the discussion of exercise down into two groups: fat loss, and muscle gain. </p>

<p><strong>How to Apply the Golden Rule to Fat Loss?</strong></p>

<p>Cutting fat requires heat, sweat, breath, and recovery.  </p>

<p>If you are stagnant in your results, then aim to produce twenty percent more heat, sweat, and breath in your workouts.  Or another option might be to add one workout a week that you’ve avoided, but know will produce this desired effect. </p>

<p>Lastly, create a new focus on recovery.  Make sure your efforts aren’t futile as a result of a lack of rest or the energy required to produce that extra twenty percent effort. </p>

<p><strong>How to Apply the Golden Rule to Muscle Gain? </strong></p>

<p>Muscle gain is much more difficult and far less understood than fat loss.  Two principles however consistently rise to the top regarding muscle growth (hypertrophy).   </p>

<p>The first principle of muscle growth is the creation of micro-tears in the muscle via stress-induced progressive overload. The second is repair. New muscle doesn't actually form without the fusion and growth of tiny fibers at the site of the microtears.  </p>


<p><strong>Principle #1 – </strong>Muscle Damage – Micro-tears</p>

<p>How can I safely increase the frequency or stress my muscles are under by twenty percent?  </p>

<p>There are a few options here and since skeletal muscle is highly adaptable it’s often good to cycle an increase in frequency with an increase in weight.  </p>

<p>Try creating a pushup, pullup, or dip challenge over the course of a month that you do in addition to your normal strength training.  Start small and over the course of the month progressively increase your repetitions each day.  </p>

<p>Then next month challenge yourself to increase the weight you’re lifting by twenty percent over 30 days.  Just make sure you gradually increase and use proper mechanics.  </p>

<p><strong>Principle #2 –</strong> Muscle Repair </p>

<p>How can I increase the nutrients my body needs for muscle health by twenty percent?  </p>

<p>Research the supplements, foods, and vitamins that aid in muscle growth and repair.  Focus on the areas in your research where you feel you might be deficient.  Then pick one or two items to increase over the course of the next 30 days.  </p>

<p>How can I increase my sleep or improve my recovery by twenty percent? </p>

<p>Start paying attention to the times you go into Monday’s workout feeling the strongest.  What might have been the cause of this result?  Did you get good sleep?  Did you give yourself an extra day of recovery?  Maybe you did yoga or increased your stretching.  </p>

<p>Whatever the case may be, your goal is to replicate this week in and week out. </p>

<p>Why?  Because now you know this is one of those twenty percent items worth your time and attention.  Remember this whole exercise is about focus!</p>

<p><strong>Let’s Recap and Finish with a Call to Action!</strong></p>

<p>As is the case with almost everything in life, it’s not how much you do, but what you do that is important.  </p>

<p>When it comes to health and wellness, we waste a lot of time half-assing our way thru diet and exercise.  Understanding that twenty percent of efforts produce eighty percent of our results helps generate focused planning. </p>

<p>While at first it might seem like we are only adding to our plate by removing twenty percent of the items, this is short-term pain for a long-term gain.  </p>

<p>Over time, with a renewed focus, we start to realize the eighty percent of futile food and effortless exercise that doesn’t produce.  What is left is pure gold courtesy of the Pareto Principle! </p>

<p>If this makes sense to you, then decide what fitness goal you find yourself coming up short on and use the 80/20 rule to find your renewed focus.  Write down the factors that are most important in changing.  Get curious about what these changes might do to improve your health and wellness.  Implore “want power” over “will power” and create new rewards for your efforts.  With the right focus and properly executed practice, we can achieve almost anything we want! </p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Maximize Your Macros: 6 Rules to Live By For Fats, Proteins, and Carbs]]></title><description><![CDATA[Eat fat get fat.  Eat protein get big muscles.  Eat a lot of carbs and you’ll get soft in the middle. As is the case with most myths, there ]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/maximize-your-macros-6-rules-to-live-by-for-fats-proteins-and-carbs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">617470678a078f0016b376e1</guid><category><![CDATA[health and wellness]]></category><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 20:43:40 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_7f87714953a5457f9c16306314c5654b~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_534,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_7f87714953a5457f9c16306314c5654b~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_534,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Eat fat get fat.  Eat protein get big muscles.  Eat a lot of carbs and you’ll get soft in the middle. As is the case with most myths, there is a hint of truth behind these commonly held beliefs, but for the most part, our macros are misunderstood.  </p>

<p>Let’s discuss how to maximize our macros in this week’s tip. </p>


<p><strong>Fat – If fat made us fat, then how do so many achieve success on Keto? </strong></p>

<p>Two important things to understand about fat. </p>

<p><strong>Rule #1</strong>. There are different kinds of fat and they aren’t all equal.  Saturated fats are solid at room temperature and typically are known as the "bad fats".  Think bacon grease. Unsaturated fats are liquid at room temperature and are generally known as the "healthy fats".  Think oils. Then there are also manufactured fats that can be found in processed foods.  These come under a variety of ever changes names so pay attention to labels. When choosing your fats aim for the unsaturated choice and stay away from processed foods.  </p>

<p><strong>Rule #2</strong>. Fat has 9 calories per gram whereas carbs and proteins each have 4 calories per gram.  Simply put, you get fewer calories per gram on a high-fat diet. This is why you often see fasting as part of the Keto and high-fat diets.  </p>

<p><strong>Protein – If high protein diets made everyone bulky with muscle then how did so many get skinny on Atkins? Also, if high protein intake is required to get big muscles how can a bull, a gorilla, and world-record-holding strong man Patrik Baboumian get big on plant power? </strong></p>

<p>Two important things to understand about protein. </p>

<p><strong>Rule #1.</strong> Protein breaks down slower in the body and is generally more “filling” than carbohydrates but has 5 fewer calories per gram than fat and equal calories to carbs.  </p>

<p><strong>Rule#2.</strong> Proteins aren’t just found in animal products.  You can get the essential amino acids needed entirely from a vegetarian-only diet. Protein is found in red beans, nuts, rice, whole grains, and all sorts of veggies! </p>

<p><strong>Carbs- If carbs made us soft then how does our trainer Shane maintain less than 10% body fat on a high carb diet? </strong></p>

<p>Two important things to understand about carbohydrates. </p>

<p><strong>Rule #1.</strong> Carbohydrates break down into glucose.  Glucose binds together in “bundles” called glycogen and is stored in the muscles for energy as fuel for the body. Excess glycogen however can convert to adipose tissue, aka fat.  </p>

<p><strong>Rule #2. </strong>There are healthy and unhealthy carbs.  Healthy carbs tend to break down slower and be higher in fiber content.  As is the case with all good diets stay away from processed foods and added sugar. When you eat sugar, it hits the liver so quickly that it can’t convert it all which leads to excess glucose and glycogen production.  Eating added sugar is like hooking yourself up to an IV of fat production! </p>

<p>So, if we want to maximize our macros we need to avoid processed foods that often circumvent the processes by which our body breaks down macronutrients.  If you can pick it, grow it, and identify it as a plant or animal then chances are you are maximizing your nutrients.  Keep your calories under what you burn and you will lose weight. If you want to grow muscle make sure you have enough calories to fuel your body's needed recovery.  Last, but not least, stay the hell away from added sugar which is the surest way to cannonball any fitness goal! </p>

<p>If you like our tips, follow our facebook page or subscribe @ <a href="www.myfitnesssuites.com" target="_blank" ><u>www.myfitnesssuites.com</u></a> </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Willpower is Overrated! Use This Instead...]]></title><description><![CDATA[Willpower is overrated!  Use this instead...]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/willpower-is-overrated-use-this-instead</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6169cfa8e82183001604f822</guid><category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 20:18:31 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_ee2cfb9f3e7c4e11b450dfd671ace999~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_534,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_ee2cfb9f3e7c4e11b450dfd671ace999~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_534,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Willpower is OVERRATED! The more we think about and deny ourselves the reward the more we want it.  Why is that and what can we do instead?  </p>

<p>Stress is often the trigger of many of our bad habits.  The challenge is that in the process of reward denial, and failure, we create more stress and more triggers.  Many habit change experts and psychologists believe the better method of habit change is to reverse the process and start at the WANT.  </p>

<p>Let’s use an example to illustrate. </p>

<p>Say you have a bad habit of drinking too much.  Think back to your first drink.  Did you enjoy the taste?  Did you drink to avoid stress?  </p>

<p>Probably not. </p>

<p>But everyone around you touted the benefits of alcohol, and you kept trying.  Eventually, with routine and practice, you saw the calming effects others did.  You learned to mix the alcohol with other things that made it taste better.  You learned how to avoid some of the negative side effects.  </p>

<p>Then, at some point, you get so good at it that you fail to realize your habit is creating the stress that causes you to want it. In fact, you get so routine in this practice that you fail to recognize that the very thing you did to reduce stress is now causing you additional stress. </p>

<p>So now you want to quit or cut back by denying yourself the very thing you still believe is the best remedy for your problem. How’s that going to work? I feel stressed just thinking about it. </p>

<p>What if instead of reward denial you go back to the beginning and start over with a new want and reward?  How might you reduce your stress starting from a standpoint not of quitting but simply of curiosity? How much easier might it be to change your drinking habit because you want to instead of forcing the issue? </p>

<p>By starting from a place of want instead of will we set ourselves up to create a new habit that quite possibly replaces the old with better results.  Habits are all formed through cue and reward.  Denying yourself of the reward and ignoring the cue is a tough road. </p>

<p>Instead, start with a mindset of not wanting what you currently have and instead repeat the process again with a new WANT.  From there set up a new system of cue and reward to keep you on track.   </p>

<p>If you want to get fit, then start by understanding what habits led to your deteriorating health.  Get curious and focus on the potential reward instead of the pain that denial might induce.  How much money will I save? How much better will I feel? How much more energy will I have?   </p>

<p>Practice and repeat and eventually, the new cue and reward becomes automatic! Usually, after 10 days we start to see a steep reduction in cravings as the brain creates new neuropathways. Most experts believe it takes anywhere from 21-66 days for most to create a new habit that sticks.  That's not that long to do something possibly life-changing.</p>







]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Secret Sauce For Successful Weight Loss - 4 Formulas for Faster Results]]></title><description><![CDATA[4 secret formulas to weight loss success! ]]></description><link>https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/post/the-secret-sauce-for-successful-weight-loss-4-formulas-for-faster-results</link><guid isPermaLink="false">615b56fe6d2c0a00174afae0</guid><category><![CDATA[health and wellness]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 23:32:03 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_19d67ce7f691413d9e613f0cde84a34c~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_534,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Tyler Menke</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/dba0d2_19d67ce7f691413d9e613f0cde84a34c~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_940,h_534,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>“Fail fast.” “Learn from past experiences.” “Never stop searching.”  “Surround yourself with the best.” “Work smarter not harder.”  </p>

<p>We have all heard these sayings, right?</p>

<p>Things that are often repeated generation after generation tend to carry merit.  </p>

<p>The impetus for our Tip of the Week series is to share some of the lesser-known industry secrets related to health and wellness.  But, in just the same way we all needed to hear the phrases above multiple times before using them to our benefit, often the best ideas need some repeating. </p>

<p>So, each month we will pull the top tips and concepts from the prior month's weekly message and bullet point them in a blog post.  </p>

<p>Here are some highlights worth revisiting from September.</p>
<h3><strong>Secret #1 The formula for weight loss success!  </strong></h3>
<p><strong>Calories = Energy </strong></p>
<p><strong>Fat = Stored Energy</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fat Loss = Energy Consumption < Energy Burned</strong></p>
<p><strong>1lb fat = Roughly 3500 calorie deficit</strong></p>

<p><strong>Example: Gwen weighs 175 lbs.  She is 40 years old. 5’4 tall with 38% body fat. Her daily calorie consumption is 2400 and her active calorie burn is 2100.  </strong></p>

<p><strong>She has 2 ways to lose fat: </strong></p>

<p><strong>Way 1. Change her consumption from 2400 to 1900.  Doing this she will have a deficit of 200 calories a day from her burn number of 2100. After 12 weeks she will weigh roughly 170lbs. (90days X 200 =18000 cal/3500 = 5lbs)</strong></p>

<p><strong>Way 2. Change her consumption to 1900 and add 5 days of blood-pumping exercise!  Doing this she will have a deficit of roughly 575 calories a day.  After 12 weeks she will weigh roughly 160lbs.(90 days x 575 = 51,700 cal/3500 = 15lbs)</strong></p>
<h3><strong>Secret #2 The formula for faster weight loss</strong></h3>
<p><strong>Weekly Snapshot</strong></p>

<p><strong>60 mins of cardio + 2-4hrs of strength + 1-2 hours of stretching or yoga</strong></p>

<p><strong>Strength training and HIIT outpace cardio only modalities for 2 reasons</strong></p>

<p><strong>Reason 1: Afterburn – We continue to burn for 48-72 hours after strength and HIIT training as our bodies expel energy to repair themselves. </strong></p>

<p><strong>Reason 2: Muscle gained increases our metabolic rate at rest.  Muscle burns 3x what fat does at rest.  The higher the muscle to fat ratio, the higher the metabolic rate of burn. </strong></p>
<h3><strong>Secret #3 Stress = Weight Gain</strong></h3>
<p><strong>Stress causes cortisol and adrenaline levels to spike.  This is normal.  Our body interprets stress as a need for increased fuel.  Think in terms of times of old and imagine being face to face with a bear.  The body tells the brain we need all systems on deck.  We better run and we better burn with everything we got!!!  </strong></p>

<p><strong>The problem arises when we have too much stress with no real threat requiring the additional burn.  So, when it comes to stress eating, we need to realize the phycological and physical components and address them separately.  </strong></p>

<p><strong>How to overcome stress eating? </strong></p>

<p><strong>1. Psychological – Divert the BEAR!!! – Recognize when it’s stress causing you to eat and plan and prepare diversions.  Are you stressed at night? Maybe it's stress when the kids get off the bus?  The morning?  </strong></p>

<p><strong>When do you eat to compensate for this?  Find diversions for 10 days for these times and the body adapts. </strong></p>

<p><strong>2. Physical – Kill the BEAR!!!! – The legs and glutes house the biggest muscles in our bodies.  Drop and do 15 deep squats every time you feel the stress eating coming on and this will trick the body into thinking you’ve now overcome the stress that would have required more consumption.  </strong></p>

<h3><strong>Secret #4 – Cross Train</strong></h3>
<p><strong>Tis the season for running with the Queen Bee and Flying Pig just around the corner.  Running is a great stress relief and builds our cardio endurance.  In addition, having a fitness goal helps keep us motivated! Running however is one of the higher injury-related forms of exercise out there.  It puts a lot of stress on the joints that only gets compounded when we run carrying weight our body wasn’t intended to carry.  One of the best ways to stay injury-free and continue on a fitness journey while training for a marathon is cross training.  </strong></p>

<p><strong>Here is a snapshot of what a cross-training week might look like for runners out there! </strong></p>

<p><strong>  </strong></p>
<p><em><strong>Monday- long run, Tuesday- upper body strength followed by yoga, Wednesday-recovery, Thursday-speed work, sprints, and lower body strength, Friday- yoga and core, Saturday: hill run day, Sunday-recovery.  </strong> </em></p>


<p><strong>Ok</strong>,<strong> that's a wrap on September's recap!  If you like our tips and want more free content, follow our Facebook page and </strong><a href="https://www.myfitnesssuites.com/" target="_blank" ><strong><u>subscribe</u></strong></a><strong> to our mailing list!  </strong></p>

<p><strong>And remember, "It's My Body, My Mind, My Life" so go own it!!!</strong></p>



]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>